Mss.B.P274 Mss.B.P274
American Philosophical Society
- Series One: Papers
  - Charts to better enable seamen to find latitude and longitude., Undated; Garnett, John, 1748 or 51-1820
    Engravings. 4p.and add. to Robert Patterson. Various sizes. (see Patterson Papers.) These are probably page proofs sent by Garnett to R. Patterson.
  - Nov. 2; Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, Undated; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Garnett, John, 1748 or 51-1820
    New Brunswick, A.L. 1p.and add.,end. Mutilated. (see Patterson Papers.) Concerning his aid to navigation.
  - Supplement for tables to be used in finding latitude and longitude., Undated; 16-1/2x10; Garnett, John, 1748 or 51-1820
    A.D. 2p. Sent to Robert Patterson. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - May 3; Letter to R[obert Maskell] Patterson, Undated; 10x8; Huerta, A. J.
    A.L.in 3d P. 1p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Will give another concert. On address sheet are miscellaneous notes by R.M.Patterson.
  - Memorandum on iron, Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    nickel and cobalt. A.D. 4p. (see Patterson Papers.) Not found April, 2011.
  - Analytical spherical trigonometry problems, Undated; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    solutions and many notes on the subject. A.D. 1vol.consisting of paper covers with engraved portrait of B.Franklin on cover,and 20 leaves,of which 19 contain writing. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Astronomical problem., Undated; 15x10; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 3p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Astronomical problem in spherical trigonometry., Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Auxiliary table for the calculation of logarithms., Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Botany classification., Undated; 8-1/2x7; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 3p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Calculations and notes on curves, Undated; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    surfaces of solids, etc. A.D. 52 leaves. Various sizes. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Calculations of heat from different types of coal., Undated; 7-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Calculations on gold and silver coins., Undated; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Compendium of Fluxions or the differential calculus., Undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1vol.consisting of 28 leaves, of which 19 contain writing. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Compendium of natural philosophy,etc., Undated; 7-1/4x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1vol.consisting of 28 leaves of which 27 contain writing. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Concerning a code to be used by the navy., Undated; 9x7; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. (see Patterson papers) Contains mathematical problem on the reverse.
  - Concerning algebra., Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. Incomplete. (see Patterson Papers.) Beginning of an elemental treatise on algebra.
  - Concerning coal., Undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Concerning concerts., Undated; 9x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Concerning cubic equations., Undated; 12-1/2x8 and 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 7p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Concerning electricity, according to Faraday., Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p. In pencil. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Concerning Gregory's chapter on eclipses., Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Concerning music audiences "for the consideration of J.K. Kane Esqr.", Undated; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.d. 2p.,add. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Concerning parallels., Undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p. (see Patterson papers)
  - Concerning rotaries., Undated; 5x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. (see Patterson Papers)
  - Concerning the combination lock invented by Regnier., Undated; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Concerning the combination lock (to be exhibited at the academy)., Undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Concerning the Pennsylvania company for insurances on lives and granting annuities., Undated; 12-1/2x8 and 8x4-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    D. 1p.and 2p.of tables. and (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Concerning the pump., Undated; 9x7; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 6p. (see Patterson Papers) Dealing with mathematics.
  - Concerning the types of audiences at concerts [for J.K.Kane?], Undated; 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 5p. (see Patterson Papers.) On one page is an extract of a description of Haydn playing.
  - A defense of curiosity, delivered to the Delaware county institute of science., Undated; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 36p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.) Describes Franklin's electrical kite experiment. Concerning Priestley and gasses, astronomy etc.
  - Examination in astronomy., Undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Examination in chemistry., Undated; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Examination in dynamics., Undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 3p. (see Patterson Papers) On reverse of American Botanical Society. The American Botanical Society...have elected...; 180-. Not found April, 2011.
  - Examination in mechanics [mathematics]., Undated; 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Examination on Cavallo's Natural Philosophy., Undated; 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1vol.with marbled paper cover [containing lable "Sold by Joseph G. Auner"], consisting of 20 leaves, of which 9 contain writing. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Geometry notes., Undated; 8x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 10p. (see Patterson papers
  - Lecture on natural philosophy., Undated; 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 18p. (see Patterson Papers.) Introductory lecture (?) to a course. Mentions the APS.
  - Lecture on natural philosophy at the University of Pennsylvania., Undated; 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p. Incomplete. (see Patterson Papers.) Refers to Peale's museum, the APS, and the Academy of natural sciences.
  - April 12, 13, 22; Lectures on heat and electricity, Undated; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Letter to the trustees of the University of Pennsylvania., Undated; 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.L. 11p.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Suggests ways of improving the college.
  - List of electrical equipment., Undated; 8-1/2x4-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. In French. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - List of laboratory apparatus for experiments in electricity, galvanism, optics and heat., Undated; 8x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 4p. In pencil. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - List of references to be consulted, Undated; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    in natural philosophy. A.D. 1p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - A list of subjects for study in natural philosophy., Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Mathematical notes., Undated; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    D. 1vol.consisting of 23 leaves of which 15 contain writing: with marbled covers. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Mathematical scraps..., Undated; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Mathematics of the water wheel., Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Memoir on binomial theorems., Undated; 13x7-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Memorandum on iron, nickel and cobalt., Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Miscellaneous astronomical problems with formulas taken from Garnett, Undated; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    etc. A.D. 9p.of various sizes. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Miscellaneous mathematical papers., Undated; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 37 leaves of various sizes, and two labels. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Miscellaneous notes of natural philosophy, Undated; 7x3; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    students at the University of Virginia, and the Leiper canal. A.D. 8p. (see Patterson papers
  - Miscellaneous notes used in lectures on natural philosophy., Undated; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 9p.of various sizes. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Notes from Burja's geometry., Undated; 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Notes:, Undated; 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Hydrostatics; hydraulics, astronomy, etc. A.D. 16p. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Notes of an astronomical lecture delivered before the Athenian institute., Undated; 10x7-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 19p.and wrapper. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Notes of Greek grammar., Undated; 12x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Notes of Hebrew grammar., Undated; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    D. 2p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Of curves., Undated; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2vols.with marbled covers, consisting of 20 leaves each [with label of Thomas Desilver on covers]. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - On solmisation., Undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. Fragment. (see Patterson Papers.) Has mathematical problems on same sheet.
  - Outline for lectures in chemistry., Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Pneumatics:, Undated; 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Aerostatics, electricity, astronomy, etc. D. 1vol.consisting of 32 leaves. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Problem for R. P[atterson] in ballistics., Undated; 8x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 4p. (see Patterson papers)
  - Problems, Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    etc., in geometry, selected for the American philosophical society. A.D. 4p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Problems in natural philosophy from the Cambridge collection., Undated; 8x13; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Problems in plane trigonometry., Undated; 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1vol.in marbled covers [with label of Thomas Desilver],consisting of 20 leaves. (see Patterson papers
  - Problems in spherical geometry., Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Three pages follow, containing mathematical symbols.
  - Problems in trigonometry., Undated; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Problems of a simple pendulum., Undated; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Remarks on Bourdon's book on analytical geometry., Undated; 7-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Speculations on the subject of molecular attraction., Undated; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 13p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Speech used for the conferring of the degrees of A.B., A.M., and D.D., Undated; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p. In Latin. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Syllabus of a course in anatomy., Undated; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Synoptic table of salts., Undated; 15x15-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Memorandum [of an eclipse?]., Undated; 2-1/2x8; Wistar, Caspar, 1761-1818
    D.S. 1p. In pencil. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - The doctrine of parallel lines., Undated; 13x8; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    A.D.S. 4p. (see Patterson Papers.) Read to the American philosophical society.
  - March 28; Note to Robert Patterson, Undated; 8x5; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.N.S. 1p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Sends request by Adrian to him.
- Series Two: Bound Volumes, B P274.1 (Volume 1-5)
  5 Bound Volumes.
  - Volume 1: Lectures on algebra, 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert, 1819-1909 (Volume 1)
    "Written by my father, Robert Maskell Patterson." D. 1 vol.consisting of 62 leaves,of which 54 contain writing. In same book as: R. Patterson. Omnium Gatherum; Aug. 1836.
  - Volume 2: Omnium Gatherum, Aug. 1836; 7-1/2x6; Patterson, Robert, 1819-1909 (Volume 2)
    A.D.S. 1 vol. consisting of 62 leaves, of which 54 contain writing, end.: "Presented by Robert Maskell Patterson to his Sister Emma F. Patterson. May the 18th. 1837." In same book is: R. Patterson. Lectures on algebra...
  - Volume 3: Account book with many pages of scientific notes, 12-3/4x8-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Volume 3)
    Examples, problems,theories, etc. on various subjects: conic sections, ellipses, hyperbola, Newton, etc. D. 1 vol. consisting of 68 leaves.
  - Volume 4: Application of algebra to the invention and demonstration of theorems in various parts of mathematics: material pertaining to the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia: and, miscellaneous notes on mathematics, Feb. 27, 1809; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Ingraham, Edward Duncan, 1793-1854 (Volume 4)
    A.D.S. 1 vol. consisting of 79 leaves.
  - Volume 5: Miscellany, 12-3/4x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854 (Volume 5)
    Register of clock's rate with notes on transit instrument and time: account book: eclipse of the sun: calculations of longitude by Bowditch's rules: personal observations, etc; 1800-1831. A.D.